Guide to the Northup & O'Brien Architectural Records
Northup & O'Brien Architectural Records
1917-1980
1917 1980
Northup & O'Brien Winston-Salem, N.C.
MC 00240
The Northup & O'Brien Architectural Records document the work of Northup & O'Brien, an architectural firm in Winston-Salem, North Carolina, and its successors. The collection consists primarily of architectural drawings and job specifications, 1917-1980, as well as financial material, 1917-1956. The drawings represent the variety of projects undertaken by Northup & O'Brien in Winston-Salem as well other locations across the state, including residences, businesses, hospitals, schools, churches, and public and educational buildings. Most of the drawings are original, and characterize the different kinds of materials used for architectural drawing over the twentieth century.
The firm of Northup & O'Brien was established in Winston-Salem by Willard Close Northup and Leet Alexander O'Brien in 1916. The partnership and its successor firms designed and constructed buildings in Winston-Salem and throughout North Carolina, as well as outside the state. In addition to residences--particularly fine homes--the partnership also specialized in commercial structures, schools, hospitals, churches, and municipal, county, and state government buildings.
184 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Transferred from the Southern Historical Collection, Wilson Library, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1997 July 10 (Accession no. 1997-0012); gifts of Louis William Pope of Kernersville, North Carolina, 1981; Newman Calloway Johnson Winfree of Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 1981; and Charlotte Vestal Brown of Raleigh, North Carolina, 1982.
This collection is divided into three series: Drawings, Specifications, and Financial Material.
Willard Close Northup (1882-1942) began practicing as an architect in Winston-Salem, North Carolina, in 1906. Leet Alexander O'Brien (1891-1963) joined Northup's office as a draftsman the following year, and in 1916 the two established the partnership of Northup & O'Brien. O'Brien retired in 1952, a decade after Northup's death, and the following year the firm changed its name to Lashmit James Brown & Pollock. After a series of subsequent changes (see below), the firm became Calloway Johnson Moore & West in 1994.
The firm was known by the following names during the periods indicated:
Willard C. Northup, 1906-1916Northup & O'Brien, 1916-1953Lashmit James Brown & Pollock, 1953-1962Lashmit Brown & Pollock, 1962-1971Jennings Newman VanEtten Winfree, 1971-1972Newman VanEtten Winfree Associates, 1972-1977Newman Calloway Johnson VanEtten Winfree, 1977-1980Newman Calloway Johnson Winfree, 1980-1984Calloway Johnson Moore, 1984-1994Calloway Johnson Moore & West, 1994-
Northup & O'Brien and its successor firms designed and constructed buildings in Winston-Salem and throughout North Carolina, as well as outside the state. In addition to residences--particularly fine homes--the partnership also specialized in commercial structures, schools, hospitals, churches, and municipal, county, and state government buildings.
The Northup & O'Brien Architectural Records document the work of Northup & O'Brien, an architectural firm in Winston-Salem, North Carolina, and its successors. The collection consists primarily of architectural drawings and job specifications, 1917-1980, as well as financial material, 1917-1956. The drawings and specifications are for residences, hospitals, churches, and educational, commercial, and public buildings. These projects were undertaken chiefly in Winston-Salem, but also in other locations across the state. Most of the drawings are original, and characterize the different kinds of materials used for architectural drawing over the twentieth century.
Northup & O'Brien Winston-Salem, N.C.; Northup Willard C. 1882-1942; O'Brien Leet A. 1891-1963; Architecture; Account books; North Carolina Architects; North Carolina 20th century Architectural drawing; Architectural drawings; North Carolina Architectural firms; Drawings; Financial statements; Buildings, structures, etc. Winston-Salem (N.C.)
- Drawings, 1917-1980
  This series consists of drawings produced for architectural projects. Included are comprehensive plans, as well as specialized plans for such components of jobs as plumbing, heating, electrical wiring, and landscaping. Also included are architectural projects of Willard C. Northup. The drawings represent the variety of projects undertaken by Northup & O'Brien in the Winston-Salem area and elsewhere, including residences, businesses, hospitals, schools, churches, and public and educational buildings. Specifications for some, but not all, of these drawings are located in Series 2, Specifications. This series is arranged alphabetically by job name. Following each job name is the commission number and the county name in which the property is or was located.
  - Adams, John Hampton - Barn, 1929 (Flatfolder 181)
    Guilford County, N.C.
  - Adams, John Hampton - Residence, 1929 (Flatfolder 33)
  - Adderson, James - Residence, 1921 (Flatfolder 515)
    Davidson County, N.C.
  - Albemarle City Hall, 1938 (Flatfolder 290)
    Stanly County, N.C.
  - Amos and Smith Hosiery Mill - Addition, 1958 (Flatfolder 490)
    Surry County, N.C.
  - Amos Hosiery Mill - Addition, 1953 (Flatfolder 42)
  - Amos Hosiery Mill - Factory Building, 1941 (Flatfolder 71)
  - Amos, R. T. - Residence - Alterations, 1934 (Flatfolder 30)
  - Anchor Dept. Store - Alteration and Addition, 1938 (Flatfolder 294)
    Forsyth County, N.C.
  - Anderson, Fred - Residence, 1928 (Flatfolder 151)
  - Apartment Building for J. R. Thomas - Alterations, 1934 (Flatfolder 192)
  - Appalachian State Teachers College - Boy's Dorm, 1950 (Flatfolder 72)
    Watauga County, N.C.
  - Appalachian State College - Laundry Building, 1948 (Flatfolder 541)
  - Appalachian State Teachers College - Boys Dormitory, 1950 (Flatfolder 331)
  - Appalachian State Teachers College - Girls' Dorm, 1950 (Flatfolder 330)
  - Appalachian State University - Library - Alterations and Additions, 1954 (Flatfolder 340)
  - Appalachian State University - Music and Art Building, 1950 (Flatfolder 329)
  - Aquadale School, 1948 (Flatfolder 464)
  - Archdale School, 1936 (Flatfolder 389)
    Archdale, Guilford County, N.C.
  - Ardmore Moravian Church (also contains Ardmore M. E. Church), 1924, 1931 (Flatfolder 438)
    Winston-Salem, Forsyth County, N.C.
  - Ardmore School - Addition, 1954 (Flatfolder 343)
  - Ashby, Edward - Residence, 1937 (Flatfolder 289)
  - Asheboro School, 1935 (Flatfolder 269)
    Asheboro, Randolph County, N.C.
  - Atkins High School Gymnasium, 1950 (Flatfolder 333)
  - Augsburg Lutheran Church, 1977 (Flatfolder 23)
  - Badin School - Gymnasium, 1947 (Flatfolder 322)
  - Bagley, Smith W - Kent Road drawings, 1972 (Flatfolder 560)
  - Bahnson, A. H. - Residence, 1919 (Flatfolder 127)
  - Bahnson, Fred - Residence, 1922 (Flatfolder 116)
  - Balfours School Building, 1926 (Flatfolder 395)
    Randolph County, N.C.
  - Barbee - Residence, 1929 (Flatfolder 32)
  - Barber, Thomas - Residence, 1941 (Flatfolder 454)
  - Barnes, H. R. - Residence, 1925 (Flatfolder 131)
  - Bellamy, Hargrove - Residence, 1933 (Flatfolder 439)
    New Hanover County, N.C.
  - Benton, M. C. - Residence, 1971 (Flatfolder 237)
  - Bernhardt Administrative Building, 1937 (Flatfolder 445)
  - Bernhardt, George H. - Residence, 1940 (Flatfolder 453)
    Caldwell County, N.C.
  - Bethesda School, 1924 (Flatfolder 356)
    Durham County, N.C.
  - Bethlehem Community Center, 1964 (Flatfolder 216)
  - Biscuit Kitchen, Inc., 1978 (Flatfolder 13)
    Cumberland County, N.C.
  - Blackburn, C. A. Residence, 1937 (Flatfolder 444)
  - Blair, D. H. - Theatre Building, 1930 (Flatfolder 434)
  - Boonville School - Alterations and Additions, 1935 (Flatfolder 268)
    Yadkin County, N.C.
  - Bowman Gray Institute of Medicine, 1941 (Flatfolder 471)
  - Bowman Gray Residence (Graylyn) (Tube 4)
  - Bowman Gray School of Medicine, 1940 (Flatfolder 307)
  - Bowman Gray School of Medicine - Wake Forest College, 1940 (Flatfolder 306)
  - Bowman Gray School of Medicine - Wake Forest College, 1940 (Flatfolder 336)
  - Breach, William- Residence (Flatfolder 298)
  - Brice, Robert - Residence, 1973 (Flatfolder 492)
  - Brown, George - Residence, 1929 (Flatfolder 536)
    Alleghany County, N.C.
  - Bryant Jr., V. S. - Residence, 1924 (Flatfolder 437)
  - Buena Vista School, 1953 (Flatfolder 338)
  - Bull, Irving S. - Residence, 1927 (Flatfolder 134)
  - Butler, W. M. Residence, 1946 (Flatfolder 18)
  - Caldwell County Library, 1956 (Flatfolder 512)
  - Calvary Moravian Church, 1925 (Flatfolder 377)
  - Camel City Bus Company- Garage, 1927 (Flatfolder 539)
  - Carolina Cotton and Wool Mills Company - School Building, 1920 (Flatfolder 226)
    Virginia
  - Carter, Delphine - Residence, 1926 (Flatfolder 91)
  - Carver High School, 1975 (Flatfolder 241)
  - Cash, T. H. - Residence, 1924 (Flatfolder 429)
  - Centenary United Methodist Church - Children's Building Alterations, 1977 (Flatfolder 76)
  - Central Grade School, 1922 (Flatfolder 367)
  - Chatham Manufacturing Company - Office Building, 1936 (Flatfolder 68)
  - Chatham, Thurmond - Chapel, 1927 (Flatfolder 385)
  - Children's Home - Administration Building, 1929 (Flatfolder 139)
  - Children's Home - Athletic Director Cottage, 1934 (Flatfolder 188)
  - Children's Home - Boy's Dorm, 1924 (Flatfolder 359)
  - Children's Home - Boys and Girl's Dorms, 1940 (Flatfolder 309)
  - Children's Home - Church School, 1964 (Flatfolder 392)
  - Children's Home - Community House, 1936 (Flatfolder 420)
  - Children's Home - Dormitory, 1950 (Flatfolder 481)
  - Children's Home - Dormitory, 1926 (Flatfolder 357)
  - Children's Home - Double House, 1940 (Flatfolder 538)
  - Children's Home - Girl's Dorm, 1936 (Flatfolder 417)
  - Children's Home - Girls Dormitory, 1927 (Flatfolder 142)
  - Children's Home - Norfleet Building (Boys Dormitory), 1935 (Flatfolder 275)
  - Children's Home School Building - Addition, 1948 (Flatfolder 326)
  - China Grove Township School Building, 1936 (Flatfolder 397)
    China Grove, Rowan County, N.C.
  - City National Bank - Branch Bank, 1957 (Flatfolder 197)
  - Clemmons Condominium, 1979 (Flatfolder 84)
  - Clemmons Consolidated School, 1924 (Flatfolder 207)
  - Clemmons Moravian Church - Addition, 1979 (Flatfolder 85)
  - Clemmons School - Addition, 1936 (Flatfolder 285)
  - Clemmons School - Gym, 1939 (Flatfolder 281)
  - Coan, John - Residence, 1942 (Flatfolder 470)
  - Cobb, I. W. - Cottage, 1935 (Flatfolder 270)
  - Coleridge School, 1936 (Flatfolder 568)
  - Coley, S. B. - Residence and Garage, 1939 (Flatfolder 457)
    Wake County, N.C.
  - Colored Grade School, 1922 (Flatfolder 200)
    Rowan County, N.C.
  - Columbia Heights Colored School, 1921 (Flatfolder 379)
  - Columbia Heights Colored School - Alterations and Additions, 1929 (Flatfolder 172)
  - Commercial National Bank Building, 1917 (Flatfolder 508)
    Raleigh, Wake County, N.C. This folder contains drawings by James A. Salter and P. Thornton Marye. It does NOT contain drawings by Northup O'Brien.
  - Cook's Warehouse Addition, 1958 (Flatfolder 64)
  - Cooleemee Consolidated High School, 1920 (Flatfolder 484)
    Davie County, N.C.
  - Cooper House - Old Salem, 1977 (Flatfolder 77)
  - Courtney Grade School, 1926 (Flatfolder 205)
  - Covington, Comer - Residence, 1930 (Flatfolder 35)
  - Cozart, D. L. - Residence, Alterations and Additions, 1939 (Flatfolder 296)
  - Craig, S. D. - Residence, 1925 (Flatfolder 114)
  - Craige, Burton - Swimming Pavilion, 1928 (Flatfolder 431)
  - Creech Jr., C. L. - Residence, 1932 (Flatfolder 191)
  - Creech, J. S. - Residence, 1939 (Flatfolder 456)
  - Critz School - Auditorium and Dorm, 1924 (Flatfolder 371)
  - Crumpler Motor Company, 1946 (Flatfolder 566)
  - Cummings, Pat - Residence, 1939 (Flatfolder 529)
  - Dalton, Rufus - Residence, 1926 (Flatfolder 224)
  - Danbury Courthouse, 1939 (Flatfolder 300)
    Danbury, Stokes County, N.C.
  - Davie County Health Center - Alterations and Additions, 1976 (Flatfolder 255)
  - Davie County Office Building, 1953 (Flatfolder 479)
    Mocksville, Davie County, N.C.
  - Davis Department Store - Schematic Design, 1973 (Flatfolder 233)
  - Department of Justice Building, 1938 (Flatfolder 26)
    Raleigh, Wake County, N.C.
  - Dillard, John - Residence, 1936 (Flatfolder 418)
  - Dimmette, L. E. - Residence, 1938 (Flatfolder 459)
  - Dodson, J. C. - Residence, 1927 (Flatfolder 579)
  - Draper Grade School Building, 1922 (Flatfolder 366)
    Rockingham County, N.C.
  - Drummond, D. L. - Residence, 1936 (Flatfolder 43)
  - Durham Life Insurance Building, 1941 (Flatfolder 280)
  - Durham Life Insurance Building, 1941 (Flatfolder 310)
  - Durham Life Insurance Building (Tube 1)
  - Durham Life Insurance Building - Addition, 1945 (Flatfolder 27)
  - East Fourth Street Moravian Church, 1914 (Flatfolder 103)
  - East Spencer School, 1936 (Flatfolder 564)
  - East Spencer School, 1936 (Flatfolder 564)
  - East Winston Branch Library, 1953 (Flatfolder 20)
  - East Winston Grade School, n.d. (Flatfolder 107)
  - Easton Elementary School - Addition, 1974 (Flatfolder 249)
  - Eckerd Therapeutic Wilderness Camp, n.d. (Flatfolder 75)
  - Education Building, 1952 (Flatfolder 507)
  - Efird, E. L - Cottage, 1930 (Flatfolder 264)
  - Ehringhaus, J. C. B. - Residence, 1939 (Flatfolder 303)
  - Eller, A. H. - Residence, 1917 (Flatfolder 98)
  - Ellis Street Grammar School - Addition, 1923 (Flatfolder 399)
  - Endy School - Alterations and Addition, 1936 (Flatfolder 60)
  - Endy School - Alterations and Additions, 1936 (Flatfolder 178)
  - Enochsville School, 1935 (Flatfolder 450)
  - Fain, J. R. - Addition and Alterations To Residence, 1939 (Flatfolder 554)
  - Fairview Moravian Church, 1923 (Flatfolder 209)
  - Farmer Consolidated School, 1924 (Flatfolder 213)
  - Farmer Consolidated School, 1924 (Flatfolder 214)
  - Ferrell, Luther W. - Residence, 1928 (Flatfolder 155)
  - Fillman, Scott - Residence, 1937 (Flatfolder 433)
  - First Christian Church - Sanctuary, 1959 (Flatfolder 491)
  - First Christian Church - Sunday School Building, 1956 (Flatfolder 528)
  - First Federal Saving and Loan Association, 1959 (Flatfolder 521)
  - First Presbyterian Church - Alterations and Addition, 1912 (Flatfolder 380)
  - First Presbyterian Church - Manse, 1937 (Flatfolder 184)
  - First Presbyterian Church - Manse, 1937 (Flatfolder 414)
  - First Presbyterian Church - Sunday School Building, 1932 (Flatfolder 193)
  - Flynt, George - Residence, 1930 (Flatfolder 179)
  - Follin, Marion, Mrs. - Residence, 1928 (Flatfolder 169)
  - Forbush School, 1935 (Flatfolder 267)
  - Forsyth County - Grade School, 1922 (Flatfolder 376)
  - Forsyth County Courthouse, 1974 (Flatfolder 245)
  - Forsyth County Courthouse - Alteration and Addition, 1925 (Flatfolder 543)
  - Forsyth County Mental Health Facility and Shop, 1976 (Flatfolder 250)
  - Forsyth County Mental Health Facility and Shop, 1976 (Flatfolder 251)
  - Forsyth County Mental Health Facility and Shop, 1976 (Flatfolder 252)
  - Forsyth County Mental Health Facility and Shop, 1976 (Flatfolder 253)
  - Forsyth County Mental Health Facility and Shop, 1976 (Flatfolder 254)
  - Forsyth County Mental Health Facility and Shop, 1976 (Flatfolder 256)
  - Forsyth County School Building District 3, 1920 (Flatfolder 374)
  - Forsyth County Agriculture Office Building, 1952 (Flatfolder 478)
  - Forsyth General Hospital, 1960 (Flatfolder 351)
  - Forsyth General Hospital, 1961 (Flatfolder 49)
  - Forsyth General Hospital, 1961 (Flatfolder 487)
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital, 1962-1969 (Flatfolder 546)
    Fosyth County, N.C.
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital - Alterations to ICU, 1967 (Flatfolder 3)
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital - Expansion Study, 1967 (Flatfolder 6)
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital - Long Term Care Unit, 1965 (Flatfolder 220)
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital - Nurses Residence and School, 1962 (Flatfolder 355)
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital - Rehabilitation Center, 1970 (Flatfolder 494)
  - Forsyth Memorial Hospital Rehabilitation Center, 1970 (Flatfolder 426)
  - Forsyth Tubercular Hospital, 1928-1941 (Flatfolder 29)
  - Forsyth Tuberculosis Hospital, 1938 (Flatfolder 443)
  - Forsyth Tuberculosis Hospital - Colored Ward Building, 1938 (Flatfolder 38)
  - Fourteenth Street Colored Grade School - Addition, 1929 (Flatfolder 171)
  - Foy Jr., H. S. - Residence, 1929 (Flatfolder 551)
  - Frazier County - Parking Garage and Stores, 1954 (Flatfolder 341)
  - Friends Church, 1927 (Flatfolder 52)
  - Galloway, A. H., Mrs. - Residence and Garage - Addition, 1928 (Flatfolder 148)
  - Galloway, A. H. - Cottage, 1926 (Flatfolder 89)
  - Galloway, R. S. - Residence, 1917 (Flatfolder 95)
  - Galloway, R. S. and A. C. Miller - Cottage (Flatfolder 130)
  - Garrett, C.C. - Residence, 1933 (Flatfolder 36)
  - Germantown Consolidated School, 1923 (Flatfolder 206)
    Stokes County, N.C.
  - Gilmer, John - Residence, 1928 (Flatfolder 150)
  - Glen, Jack W. - Residence, 1925 (Flatfolder 19)
  - Goldston, J. G. - Residence, 1939 (Flatfolder 31)
  - Goodson, W. A. - Residence and Garage, 1939 (Flatfolder 202)
  - Goodwill Industries - Master Plan and Addition, 1968 (Flatfolder 501)
  - Goodwill Rehabilitation Center (Flatfolder 348)
  - Goodwill Rehabilitation Center, 1959 (Flatfolder 82)
  - Goodwill Rehabilitation Center - Addition, 1963 (Flatfolder 500)
  - Goodwill Rehabilitation Center Chapel, 1969 (Flatfolder 402)
  - Gorrell, P. A. - Residence, 1931 (Flatfolder 14)
  - Gorrell, P. A.- Alterations for Store Building (Tube 2)
  - Grace Methodist Episcopal Church, 1916 (Flatfolder 90)
  - Graham, Gregory - Residence, 1930 (Flatfolder 440)
  - Graham, J. L. - Residence, 1909 (Flatfolder 266)
  - Granite Quarry School, 1936 (Flatfolder 390)
  - Gravely, J. O. W. - Residence, 1927 (Flatfolder 372)
  - Gray and Creech - Warehouse, 1928 (Flatfolder 54)
  - Gray, Bowman Estate - Farm Group, 1929 (Flatfolder 483)
  - Gray, Bowman Estate - Farm Group, 1929 (Flatfolder 510)
  - Gray, Bowman Estate - Gardener's Cottage, 1930 (Flatfolder 180)
  - Gray, Gordon - Residence, 1939 (Flatfolder 542)
  - Gray, James A. - Store Building, 1927 (Flatfolder 378)
  - Gray, James A. - Residence Alterations, 1923 (Flatfolder 111)
  - Gray, James A. - Cottage, 1926 (Flatfolder 112)
  - Gray, Natalie - Lodge, 1929 (Flatfolder 167)
  - Gray, R. F., Mrs. - Residence, 1922 (Flatfolder 196)
  - Graylyn - Residence, Addition, 1962 (Flatfolder 195)
  - Graystone Hotel - Addition, n.d. (Flatfolder 165)
  - Greensboro College - Infirmary, 1938 (Flatfolder 41)
    Greensboro, Guilford County, N.C.
  - Griffith Consolidated School - Addition, 1934 (Flatfolder 187)
  - Griffith School - Gymnasium, 1938 (Flatfolder 537)
  - Guilford College Consolidated School, 1923 (Flatfolder 381)
  - Guilford County Consolidated School, 1924 (Flatfolder 22)
  - H.U.D. - Rural Housing Proposal, 1980 (Flatfolder 97)
    North Carolina and West Virginia
  - Hanes Building, 1959 (Flatfolder 28)
  - Hanes Hosiery L'EGGS Offices, 1974 (Flatfolder 25)
  - Hanes Park Elementary School, 1958 (Flatfolder 15)
  - Hanes, Fred M. - Cottage, 1926 (Flatfolder 125)
  - Hanes, J. W., Mrs. - Residence, 1926 (Flatfolder 122)
  - Hanes, James G. - Cottage, 1925 (Flatfolder 117)
  - Hanes, P. H. - Store Buildings (1925 and 1929) (Flatfolder 160)
  - Hanes, P. H. - Store Building, c.1925 (Flatfolder 113)
  - Hanes, P. H. - Store Buildings, 1929 (Flatfolder 160)
  - Hanes, R. M. - Store, 1927 (Flatfolder 575)
  - Hawthorne Road Parking Deck, 1975 (Flatfolder 263)
  - Hawthorne Road Parking Deck, 1975 (Flatfolder 369)
  - Hayti Negro School, 1927 (Flatfolder 136)
    Durham, Durham County, N.C.
  - Henley, A. B. - Residence, 1940 (Flatfolder 45)
  - Hill Top School, 1925 (Flatfolder 524)
  - Hill Top School, 1925 (Flatfolder 577)
  - Holcomb, Lindsay - Residence and Garage, 1934 (Flatfolder 447)
  - Holton, F. P., Mrs. - Residence, 1925 (Flatfolder 102)
  - Home Economics Cottage, 1941 (Flatfolder 451)
  - Horton, Ham - Residence, 1931 (Flatfolder 175)
  - Horton, Theo. - Residence, 1930 (Flatfolder 177)
  - H.U.D. Housing - Sunwood and Sunsetwood Apartments, 1980 (Flatfolder 506)
    Wadesboro, N.C.
  - Hudson, H.G. - Residence, 1937 (Flatfolder 260)
  - Huntely Furniture Company - Factory Building - Alterations, 1947 (Flatfolder 315)
  - Huntley, Ben - Residence - Alterations and Additions, 1929 (Flatfolder 316)
  - Innis Street Grade School - Alterations and Additions, 1922 (Flatfolder 517)
  - J. F. Hurley School, 1936 (Flatfolder 277)
  - J. R. Thomas Apartment Building, 1934 (Flatfolder 573)
  - Jackson Park School, 1941 (Flatfolder 311)
  - Jackson, Edna - Residence, 1967 (Flatfolder 552)
  - James Theater, 1947 (Flatfolder 502)
    Kernersville, Forsyth County, N.C.
  - John C. Whitaker Regional Rehabilitation Center, 1970 (Flatfolder 238)
  - Johnson, J. E. - Residence, 1937 (Flatfolder 183)
    Robeson County, N.C.
  - Junior League - Charity Home, 1928 (Flatfolder 157)
  - Juvenile Relief Association of Winston Salem - Home, 1922 (Flatfolder 121)
  - Kearns, Charles L. - Residence, c.1940 (Flatfolder 48)
  - Kearns, Charles L. - Residence - Alterations, 1941 (Flatfolder 46)
  - Kernersville Elementary School - Addition, 1971 (Flatfolder 235)
  - Kernersville Jr. High - Gym, Addition, 1971 (Flatfolder 234)
  - Kernersville Jr. High School - Addition, 1973 (Flatfolder 244)
  - Kernersville School, 1926 (Flatfolder 388)
  - Kernersville School - Alterations and Additions, 1940 (Flatfolder 304)
  - Kimberly High School, 1956 (Flatfolder 346)
  - King, Walter - Residence, 1950 (Flatfolder 559)
  - Kingville Colored School Building, 1936 (Flatfolder 283)
  - Konnoak and Ardmore Jr. High; Latham Elementary, 1959 (Flatfolder 242)
  - Krispy Kreme Donut Corporation - Mix Blending Plant, 1947 (Flatfolder 318)
  - Krispy Kreme Donut Corporation - Office and Factory, 1953 (Flatfolder 337)
  - Krispy Kreme Doughnut Corporation Office - Alterations and Additions, 1964 (Flatfolder 217)
  - Landis Vocational School, 1941 (Flatfolder 527)
  - Lasater, R. E., 1938 (Flatfolder 57)
  - Lawsonville School, 1936 (Flatfolder 286)
  - Lee Memorial Presbyterian Church, 1932 (Flatfolder 520)
  - Leinbach, Clarence T. - Garage, 1929 (Flatfolder 166)
  - Leinbach, Clarence T. - Residence, Alterations and Additions, 1927 (Flatfolder 140)
  - Leinbach, Clarence T. - Residence, Alterations and Additions, 1939 (Flatfolder 301)
  - Leinbach, Clarence T. - Cottage, 1926 (Flatfolder 67)
  - Lewisville Agriculture Building, 1939 (Flatfolder 462)
  - Lewisville School, 1947-1949; 1947 1949 (Tube 3)
  - Lewisville School - Addition, 1928 (Flatfolder 146)
  - Lincoln Schools - Additions and Alterations, 1933 (Flatfolder 44)
  - Lingle's Bakery, 1945 (Flatfolder 530)
  - Locust School - Alterations and Additions, 1947 (Flatfolder 323)
  - Love Grove Church of God in Christ - Alteration, 1975 (Flatfolder 240)
  - Lower Morgan School, 1935 (Flatfolder 449)
  - Lunn, Frank - Residence, 1927 (Flatfolder 133)
  - Lutheran Church - Kane Street (Flatfolder 526)
  - Lynch, J. S. - Residence, 1924 (Flatfolder 99)
  - Malloy and Jordan Medical Building, 1946 (Flatfolder 467)
  - Marshall Fields Company - Club House, 1917 (Flatfolder 144)
  - May, Claude M. - Residential landscape survey, 1950 (Flatfolder 503)
  - McKenzie, Roy D. - Residence, 1936 (Flatfolder 284)
  - Memorial Coliseum Ice Hockey Rink, 1973 (Flatfolder 405)
  - Merrett, O. K. - Residence, 1929 (Flatfolder 257)
  - Merrit, H. L. - Residence, 1940 (Flatfolder 308)
  - Messer, J. A. - Residence, 1936 (Flatfolder 274)
  - Methodist Children's Home - Boys Dormitory, 1931 (Flatfolder 174)
  - Millingport School, 1936 (Flatfolder 421)